Well, I'm very pleased that we have
Hank Greenberg here today. We've already talked
about him and his career. Let me just
reiterate it. It's the most amazing career. It starts
when you landed on D-Day, right, on Omaha
Beach. That's amazing. At age 17, 18, a little
over 18 then. And then participated in the
liberation of Dachau at the end of World War
II. And then, not to be stopped, was involved
in the Korean War as well. And then took over
a insurance company and made it into
the most important insurance company in the world.
And experienced a number of...
A number of vicissitudes connected with that as
well. So I was asking Mr. Greenberg if
he would talk about what he did, how
he made this enormous success, what kind of... We're
interested in finance here, so it's something about
how it was financed. But that, as we've
been emphasizing in this course,
it's more than just mathematics.
It's about mathematical cap-M modeling.
It's about incentivizing people, about finding
people with the right character. And I think
that you can tell us about your experiences
and what you've learned for so many years. So
I'll turn it over to you. And then we'll
have... We'll stop at around 10, and then
we have time for a few questions from you.
All right, Mr. Greenberg.
All right.
Thank you.
Good morning.
Let me start really picking up with a professor. I
enlisted in the Army when I was 17. I hadn't
finished high school. World War II was on. I
felt I wanted to do something, and I was
bored. So I was able to fix a birth certificate.
So it said I was 18. And I thought, well, I
don't know.
I'm going to do something.
I had no problem taking me because they
weren't looking too closely. I went to Europe, went
to England first. I got there in 1943,
a year before the invasion. Spent a year training.
Left England, went to the continent, obviously on
D-Day. And went all the way through Europe,
linked up with the Russians in Linz, Austria. The
war was then over. Came back. I had to
finish high school, which was a chore. Coming back
after being in a war and going back to
high school was one of the toughest times of
my life, actually. But I did. Went on to
college and law school. Finished law school, and
the Korean War broke out. I was a reserve
officer. I had gotten commissioned
toward the end of the war.
Spent a year in Korea, separated as a
captain. Came close to staying in the military because
I was fairly young and had moved up pretty
well in rank, and was offered, trying to incentivize
me to stay in the military. But I didn't.
But I finished law school and came back. I
was married by then.
Married?
Just married.
I had a daughter, a girl that I met in college.
And had to get a job. I didn't feel like practicing
law. I didn't think, I had a law degree, I
didn't think I wanted to do that. So I was
visiting, I came back from Korea, and the next
day, went down to visit some of my friends
who I'd been, went to law school with, and
it convinced me that I didn't want to practice
law.
And as I left their office, I went
by an insurance company, a continental casualty company. And
I thought I'd see if they had a job opening.
So I went in, went up to the personnel director,
and he was kind of nasty. I had just come
back from Korea, and I came back, I had
orders to fly back, so I was really very untamed
at that moment. You know, just only about
four days before that, I still almost had
mud on my boots. And so, I went down
to the main floor, looked around the directory, and
there was a resident vice president by the
name of Bob, Bob, Bob Reed. I just walked
into his office, and said, you have a, the word
I used was not the one I use now. And,
I said, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
You know, I told him, I said, you
don't have a very good personnel director, and,
you know, I've been in the
military for about three years now.
對
I was a little more excited than that.
And I wound up getting a job.
And I started as a
junior underwriter in the insurance business.
So what is a junior underwriter?
You analyze risks and decide whether the
company wants to write those risks or not.
And I had to get a job because
I said I was married and had responsibilities.
And I kind of liked it.
I was working in what
they call the special risk division,
which was different kinds of risks almost every day.
Some were sports risks.
Some was accidental death thing for executives.
It was a whole range of
different risks you had to analyze.
I found it interesting.
I became the youngest vice president
in the history of that company.
I moved to Chicago where it's head office.
And about a couple of years later,
it's a long story so I won't take you through.
I met Star, C.V. Star, who was the
founder of the company that I chair today.
Star started his company in China in 1919.
A long time.
And obviously during World War II he had to leave.
And came back to the United States.
And he had a series of small insurance companies.
And I was intrigued with his business because
it operated outside the United States by and large.
He had one company in the
United States called the American Home.
Which really was a failure.
It was not doing well.
And he was embarrassed by that fact.
That the company.
The company was a failure.
that was not doing well that
he owned his other business he represented
American companies in doing business
overseas was called the AIU American
International underwriters it was one of a
kind and then operated mostly in Asia
one or two European countries but by and large
it was it had a it had a it's its
background was really Asian having started in
China as I said 1919 so anyway
I joined star and took over the American
home in New York which I said was was
not doing well it was a failure now
what was what was wrong with it it did
business through agents and depending upon
the skill of a company would
determine the business and the company
would determine the business and the
quality of the agents that ahead and in while
it was an old company it was it had
a very poor agency organization and so
the quality of its business was very
very very poor so it was losing money year
in and year out and the job I had
was to turn it around to cut that short I
got rid of all the agents and
went into what they call the brokerage business
sort of writing small businesses we
began writing large commercial risks and
we needed a lot of reinsurance I went
to London got Lloyd's to back that that
strategy and up to then most of
the large risks were being written in London
at Lloyd's very few American companies
had the skills to underwrite large
complicated rest whether it was large
property risk or casually or marine
aviation very difficult risk and we
assembled a group of quality underwriters
and we were and we started
doing that we ultimately became
the largest brokerage underwriting company
in the United States we were going to
run out of capital we were growing so
rapidly and successfully so I looked
around for a couple of other companies
that had the same problems that we
had before we turned it around found one
called the National Union we bought that got
rid of all of its agents and agency
business and consolidated that into
American home kept its identity because
it was a very old company one of the
current וה
the governments today.
company was one of the
world's greatest companies and the க
the oldest companies in the United States.
And then subsequently bought the New
Hampshire insurance company, did the same thing.
By now it's 19, in the mid 60s, and by
1967 I created AIG, put a holding company on top
of these three companies, and AIG was born.
In 67 I also became the head of C.V.
Starn Company, which was the owner
by and large of these insurance companies.
Starn died in 1968, but he saw
the beginning of AIG and was formed.
We also owned a life insurance company
called American Life that did business outside the
United States, and we consolidated that into AIG.
So we had both a life and
a non-life business, and we were expanding internationally.
We ultimately did business in 130 countries.
We opened markets around the world.
We introduced new types of insurance.
One of the things that made us different
was that we continued to evolve new products that
by the business, what our individuals needed.
For example, we were the first ones to introduce...
How many people are they?
directors and officers liability
insurance in the United States.
We introduced political risk insurance.
American companies doing business in
very difficult environments where their business
might be nationalized or confiscated,
we insured against those risks.
We introduced kidnap ransom insurance.
American companies doing business in not so
friendly countries where some of the employees
might be kidnapped and held for ransom.
We insured against that and we put together
a unit that helped find and get their release,
sometimes on a friendly basis,
sometimes not so friendly basis.
So we're very creative in developing products
that American business needed around the world.
We began to diversify because the
insurance business, the property casualty business is
a very...
very volatile business.
You're subject to earthquakes, you're subject
to hurricanes, you're subject to different
economic environments and that affects
the outcome of your business.
And so we wanted to diversify not
just within the property casualty business, but globally.
That's why we entered so many countries
around the world, which gave us diversification.
More diversification in your business.
Provides greater stability.
And that became one of the
things that was very important to us.
We also focused on what the expense ratio should be.
Most insurance companies are running
an expense ratio of about 30%.
We ran our company with an expense ratio of 19%.
And how did we do that?
Being the most efficient.
Using reinsurance very, very...
Very, very...
Very good.
Properly.
So we did a much better job in
both developing our business and managing the business in
a more efficient way than others would do.
And obviously you have to have an organization,
you got to surround yourself with people who
share the same values, the same aspirations that you do.
You have to have a
team that works hand in glove.
And we did.
The senior management of AIG
was like a band of brothers.
We saw things alike.
We worked well together.
I mean, there wasn't ever
a palace revolution, anything like that.
It was a great organization.
We added more diversification because that became...
Clearly diversification was essential.
But in order to do business in many countries...
You had to open the market.
Markets didn't welcome you in many countries.
Take Japan, for example.
It was a very closed market.
Japanese were very reluctant to
open their market to foreign insurers.
So we had to force the market open.
And we did.
We used...
The US government was very much on our side.
And if the Japanese didn't open their market to us...
We didn't.
We worked hard to keep some of their
own companies, whether it was insurance or otherwise, or
other things, from doing business in the United States.
We didn't hesitate to use the US government
to support our desire to open markets around
the world.
When there was negotiation on trade, for example,
most of the negotiation in the early years
was on goods.
Goods.
Goods in trade.
Things.
Not financial services.
Financial services were not negotiated at
the World Trade Negotiations, the WTO.
We brought that into being.
I served on the President's
Advisory Board for Trade Negotiations.
They never heard of negotiating financial services.
And it took us a while
to get that done, but we did.
We opened the market for
financial services to be negotiated.
And there are rules then that came into
existence so that you can negotiate trade and services.
It wasn't easy.
Even when the rules were
changed, countries dragged their feet.
Took a long time to open,
as I said, Japan, Korea, China.
It took me from 1975.
The first time I visited China.
I was in China.
To 1992, to get the first life
insurance license ever granted to a foreign company.
Moreover, all other foreign companies afterwards could
only get a license where they could
only own 49%.
We owned 100%.
And today, still, it's the only foreign
company in China, life insurance company, that owns
100% of the company.
So, it's a long way to go.
But we're going to do it.
We're going to do it.
It wasn't easy.
As I say, it took from 1975 to 1992.
And I visited China every year, a couple
of times a year to make that happen.
But we did a lot of things for China.
At the same time, we helped China.
I lobbied very hard for China's entry into
WTO, which was very important for our country
and for China, and really for the world.
So we were very active.
And you had to be in foreign policy.
So we had to be committed to foreign policy matters.
It was linked to our business.
Since we did business, as I said,
ultimately in 130 countries, it became essential that
we were at the leading edge
of what the foreign policy issues were.
We did business behind the Iron Curtain before
the Iron Curtain came down, in Hungary, Poland,
and Romania.
Moreover, I went to the Soviet Union.
during the height of the Cold War
and began a reinsurance relationship with them.
And that lasted throughout the years.
Even during the height of the Cold
War, we had a relationship going on.
It wasn't easy.
They thought I was in
the CIA most of the time.
It was a difficult thing, but we persisted.
And when the Iron Curtain came down,
we had a head start against anybody else.
Doing business in Romania and Hungary and Poland
before the curtain came down was not easy,
but we built relationships so that when it did
happen, we had a head start against anybody else.
We operated all through Latin America, the Middle East.
Parts of Africa.
And all of those are a story in themselves,
because in each country, it was a different environment,
and you had to deal
with different personalities and governments.
It was very difficult.
But we also had some basic principles.
We would never, never be involved in a bribe.
Anybody in our company that got involved
in anything like that would be fired instantly.
We understood what the foreign corrupt practice was.
We knew what the Foreign Practices Act meant before
they even had such a corrupt Foreign Practices Act.
So we had a reputation that
you didn't tamper with us that way.
And they knew also that we wouldn't
hesitate to retaliate through our government if necessary,
if they tried to keep us out of their country.
So we were tough on that basis.
We wanted open markets, and we did.
Now, you go back to what
kind of a structure did we have?
And how do you bring back the structure?
How do you bring a group of people
together that can work so harmoniously and enthusiastically together?
It's critical.
You're going to run a business like that.
You have to have an organization
that really everybody's on the same track,
and everybody is enthusiastic about what they're doing.
Our overseas people, we had what we called an MOP.
It's Mobile Overseas.
We had a lot of MOP personnel.
It was like our own State Department.
You can be working in Nigeria today
as a manager, and then six months later,
you might be in Singapore or some other country.
So you have to be mobile.
You have to be prepared to move and
not be reluctant because of one thing or another.
And becoming an MOP was a very high honor.
We didn't put — everybody couldn't get that designation.
You had to earn it.
And it was a great group of people.
But how do you motivate people to do that?
How do you get an
organization that can be so effective?
AIG at its pinnacle, when I left
in 2005, was by far the largest
and most profitable insurance company in history.
When you think about that, from a dead stop.
Now, we had a compensation structure
that was unique to the industry.
I mentioned briefly to the professor.
C.V. Starn Company was the — we considered
to be the ultimate company in the group.
It was the — it spawned AIG.
And so within the organization, it
was a very, very good organization.
And it was the only organization that was successful,
and it was the only organization that was successful.
And it was the only organization that was successful.
And it was the only organization that was
viewed as the top company in the group.
And since we spawned AIG and put
assets into AIG in exchange for AIG stock,
so that C.V. Starn and Starn International, the
two companies, owned in the beginning 100% of AIG.
As we grew and we needed
more capital, we needed more capital.
As we were growing so
rapidly, we had to raise capital.
And therefore, we got somewhat diluted.
But even at the end,
we controlled about 15% of AIG.
But the market cap was close to $200 billion from
a dead stop of $300 million when we first went public.
From $300 million to $200 billion, one
of the largest companies in the world.
So we weren't afraid of anybody taking us over.
Nobody was big enough to even to attempt that.
But what we did, we had several principles.
Nobody could earn more than a million dollars in salary.
I put that rule in.
Two, nobody would have a contract.
You stayed in AIG because you loved it
and you didn't have to have a contract.
And I refused a contract any number of times.
But we, you know, we had to.
You got bonuses based on performance.
And performance was fairly rigid.
We tried to grow our
business close to 15% a year.
And for many, many years, we achieved that growth.
The private companies that owned AIG stock, not
owned by AIG, but by the private companies,
we set up a structure where the
private companies would allocate some AIG stock.
And we would allocate some AIG
shares to individuals based on performance.
At the end of every two years, if we
hit those, hit the goals that we had established,
they'd have a certain number of AIG shares set
aside for them that they would get at retirement.
So it was golden handcuffs.
If you left the company, you left behind
the shares that were set aside for you.
And these were worth an awful lot.
So we had to do it.
We had to do it.
We had to take a lot of money.
Very few people left the company.
I can assure you that it
was a great incentive to stay.
Those are the people we wanted to
stay, the ones that got allocated shares, obviously.
It cost AIG nothing.
The public shareholders of AIG
had no cost allocated to that.
So the shareholders of AIG benefited from that.
And obviously the company overall
benefitted, because it did so well.
So it was a...
It was a great organization.
So what happened?
In 2000, in the meantime, we had further diversified.
Our life insurance business grew dramatically.
We bought a company called
Sun America, American General Life.
And so we became a
very major life and non-life company.
And then we wanted to expand
into financial services, which we did.
We had consumer finance.
We had a thrift, all of which was done because
we could benefit from all the policyholders that we had,
that we cross-market from one to the other.
And so it was natural for us to do that.
And we had an enormous—we had
close to a trillion dollars of assets
to be invested in.
Obviously.
And so we had the funds and the
capital that we needed to finance these new startups.
And that was going quite well.
One day, I had a call from Senator
Ribicoff, who was a Connecticut senator at the time.
And he wanted me to meet a young
fellow who was running a financial services business.
He had been with Drexel originally.
And he came—he was a very bright guy.
He came to us.
And we started something called AIG Financial Products.
It was a very successful company.
It did derivative business.
Everything was hedged.
It was a very successful operation.
He got a little greedy
at one point, and we separated.
He left.
We wanted him to leave.
And we put somebody else in.
He was a very, very good man.
Most of these people were all PhDs in math.
They were a special breed.
They were different.
And in order to ensure that we knew what they
were doing, we had a mirror of all the computer
systems that they used for some
of the things that they were doing.
We had one off-site that mirrored
every transaction that was being undertaken.
We also had in the company what
they call an enterprise risk management system, which
means we monitored both market risk
and credit risk throughout our organization.
Because insurance is a risk business to
begin with, and you have to monitor risk.
That was part of our nature.
We understood risk and knew how to balance it
and how to manage it in the insurance business
and the financial business as well.
After all, we had to invest a
trillion dollars of assets every year and growing.
So clearly, we had to know what we were doing.
And as I said, it was a very successful company.
In 2010, we had a very successful company.
We had a very successful company.
In 2000 and I guess it was 2004, the
end of 2004, we were reporting our earnings on
a conference call with analysts.
One of the analysts asked me
what the regulatory environment was like today.
I said, it's like a ...
A foot fault is like a murder charge.
Because things had changed dramatically
after Enron in the United States.
The regulatory system became very, very difficult.
And anything at all was ...
It really was being exaggerated
beyond what you can just believe.
The next day, we got a subpoena.
We got a subpoena from Elliot Spitzer, who
then was the Attorney General in New York.
I should say a word about this, because
there was a major change in the regulatory environment
after Enron.
And in some states, in New York
particularly, the Attorney General office has been used
as a platform to run for governor.
It became a politicized office.
And Spitzer had gone after me.
He went after my son, Jeff, who
was running Marsh McLennan, the largest insurance brokerage
firm in the United States.
He went after Sandy Weil, who was running Citigroup.
Went after Merrill Lynch.
All to promote himself as a ...
As a Attorney General who
was helping the people, quote unquote.
He destroyed several hundred billion dollars
of value, is what he did.
He got elected governor.
And you know the outcome of that.
It was a very short ...
A very short tenure.
He got caught with prostitutes and had to resign.
But he left behind a lot of broken ...
A lot of broken companies.
I was forced to leave because he threatened the
board of directors of AIG that if I didn't
leave the company, he was going to indict the company.
He went on national TV and accused
me of accounting fraud in the company.
And just before Thanksgiving, he dropped
all those charges because nobody reads the
newspapers the night before Thanksgiving.
He was a bad actor.
So I left the company in 2005.
The outcome was that ...
The plan actually had been that I would step down
as CEO in May of that year at the end
of the year.
I had a great job at the annual meeting
and remain as chairman and see how the successor
team would work.
At that point, we had 92,000 employees.
And not a small company.
To make sure that the new management team
would be able to handle the diverse businesses
that we were in.
These were all experienced people.
There was nobody new in that role.
I believe that we wanted to ...
to have the new team come
from within the company, not from outside.
Because they had to understand what we were.
And we had a culture in
the organization that was quite unique.
And you can't just change
a culture of a company instantly.
You build a culture over many, many years.
In any event, I was out.
I met the new chap who came in, Martin Sullivan,
who had been a senior
man in the organization for years.
He attended every senior staff
meeting that we had for years.
We used to meet, we had several
different, I won't go through all of that,
but several senior management meetings
that were critical to knowing
what was going on throughout
the organization on a real-time basis.
We'd meet every Monday morning.
About 15 people represented the entire organization.
They'd be reporting on everything that
was happening on a real-time basis.
We did a second meeting
held on a Wednesday every morning
that dealt with hedging full-time and risk management.
Those two subjects were on a real-time basis weekly.
And of course, there were people
working on that on a daily basis.
But anything that was out of the
ordinary would be surfaced at these meetings.
For some reason or other, he discontinued those meetings.
I can't understand why, but he did.
And what's very disturbing is that the
audit committee of AIG's board knew that
and did nothing about it.
The outcome of that was then that AIG Financial Products,
which in part is called Human
Trust Financial,
theùng trigram oftails,
and Angular Data therapy was based on,
of洗
and later was low.
which was really a product that was mostly real
estate put together and packaged and sold as a CDO.
Originally, those instruments had to have a default before a
CDS credit default swap would respond to that instrument that defaulted.
Some place along the line, that was changed
so that the instrument didn't have to default.
It simply had to lose value,
and you had to put up collateral.
The ones who issued the credit default swap had to
put up collateral equal to what the loss of value,
even though it wasn't realized, of what the CDO.
It had lost in value.
That change played a major role in what happened
in the recession that we've just been going through,
particularly on Wall Street.
Putting up more collateral meant you had
to have a lot of cash on hand.
No matter how big you were,
it became a very important issue
as to the ultimate demise of several
companies, including the problems that AIG ran into.
They were called on for billions
and billions of dollars of collateral,
which ultimately, I don't care how big you
are, you run out of cash, which they did.
One of the problems was in trying to
determine what is the value of a CDO,
since there was no price discovery,
because there was no exchange in
which you traded the CDOs on.
That was, strangely enough,
during the Clinton administration,
the Treasury Department, then run by Bob Rubin,
turned down the question of having an exchange,
and regulating credit defaults.
So, that was a big problem.
You had to get default swaps.
So, you had a situation where every
broker-dealer had a different price for a CDO.
So, what was the, you know, how much
collateral did you really need to put up
if you couldn't tell what the price of one was?
In this instance, Goldman Sachs had the lowest price
of any CDOs that were being called on for collateral.
And since AIG Financial Products did a great job,
and Goldman Sachs did a great
deal of business with Goldman Sachs,
they were being called on for more and more collateral,
they ran out of cash.
Now, the insurance companies were all very, very solvent.
They had, at state regulated, you can't
just take their capital for something else.
They were protected, all the policyholders were protected,
under the fact that there was
state law and not federal law,
that governed.
The insurance companies.
But AIG ran into difficulties.
I was not in the company.
I wouldn't have, I would have handled
it much differently had I been there.
I would not have responded to the call for collateral
when you couldn't tell what the price discovery really was.
I would have said, you know,
I should add one other thing.
AIG was a triple A
rated company when I was there.
The day I left the company,
it lost its triple A rating.
So if you were triple A rated,
you did not have to post collateral.
If you were not triple A rated,
you had to post collateral.
So, AIG ran out of cash.
So they turned to the Fed for help.
You got to remember,
this is now at a time
when Bear Stearns first got in trouble
and they found a buyer in J.P. Morgan,
which really, J.P. Morgan got
Bear Stearns for nothing practically.
There were six months in
between Bear Stearns and Lehman Brothers.
What did they do during that six months,
the government that is,
to prepare for any kind of financial upheaval.
There was no plan to deal with
what was about to descend
in the financial markets in the United States.
So Lehman Brothers,
who could have been saved by the Fed,
was let to go down.
And that caused a run on virtually all the banks.
The loss of confidence that ensued
when Lehman Brothers was let go,
going to bankruptcy,
startled the financial world.
And everybody that had any money
in any of the investment banks
or banks were pulling money out.
And so there was a,
you couldn't borrow any money,
the markets froze.
And so there was an
ad hoc approach to doing things.
So Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley,
both of which,
were going to have a problem,
were given a bank holding company license.
That gave them access to the Fed window.
And they had,
they could borrow money at very,
virtually no cost at all practical.
The Hartford Insurance Company here in Hartford,
medium sized company,
was also given a bank holding company license.
And AIG was denied one.
So AIG was the only one that
was given a bank holding company license.
And the company was left to really find a solution.
So they went to the Fed,
the New York Fed,
which I had chaired incidentally
for about seven years before.
So I knew the people in the Fed quite well.
They borrowed $85 billion from the New York Fed
at 14.5% interest.
And the Fed took 79.9%
of the equity of the company.
So they essentially nationalized the company.
Now the money that AIG got,
the $85 billion,
at these terms was just outrageous.
They then had to pay the CDOs that,
you couldn't tell what the real price was,
because there was no price discovery.
You could have negotiated
to,
to have a deal.
But AIG had a very bad deal.
And the Fed was very weak,
because the value of those
at about 40 to 60 cents on the dollar.
But the Fed made them pay
a hundred cents on the dollar.
So AIG borrowed the money,
paid Goldman Sachs and others
a hundred cents on the dollar
and had to pay that money back
to the Fed.
So things began to unravel very quickly after that.
They were losing business left and right.
They had to pay back the government.
So one thing led to another.
The Treasury put in a man by the
name of Ed Liddy to run the company.
He'd be on nobody's list to succeed running AIG.
He hadn't got a clue how to do that.
And they began to sell
off assets of AIG at prices
that were just outrageous.
So the outcome is that AIG is
a shadow of what it had been.
The government now owns 92% of AIG.
They want to sell that 92%.
It'll take at least, in
my view, three to four years
because it's an overhang.
If they sell 10%, everybody knows
there's another 80% to be sold.
And so the stock will go no place.
So do I feel bitter about it?
Yes, I do.
I feel very bitter about it.
So what am I doing?
I'm running CV Star & Company and Star International.
We're building it back into a major organization.
When I left AIG, CV
Star & Company had 300 people.
We're about 1,000 right now.
So we're running it.
So we're adding employment to the country.
And that's coming along.
We're entering it.
We're doing insurance.
We formed three new insurance companies.
We're doing business in probably
about 30 countries right now.
We have a big Lloyd's operation.
We operate throughout the European market.
We're going to China next week.
We'll have a joint venture in
China by the end of April.
We'll be in Southeast Asian countries, all
of which we know for years and years.
And we have a big investment operation.
I'm giving you a shorthand
version of what really is happening.
But how much time have I got?
Only 10 minutes.
All right.
So I think there's a lot to be done.
I think there's a lot to be done.
And I think there's a lot to think about.
Why did we get into this trouble in the country?
What brought this about?
How could a country as wise as we are
and financially literate as we are do what we
did?
And I have my own thoughts about that.
But let me just rattle some of the reasons
off that I think many was the desire in this
country during the Clinton Administration.
that housing should be an opportunity
for everybody. Everybody should have the
right to own a home.
There wasn't much differentiation whether
you can afford one or not. Historically
in our country, mortgages were granted by
local banks who knew the individual and
would work with that individual if they
got into any trouble. When the
Clinton administration decided to expand housing,
Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac were buying
mortgages from these local banks and the
local banks only serviced the mortgage,
but they really didn't have any
financial involvement after the mortgage
was sold. Clearly many people got
mortgages in homes that couldn't afford it.
So that's the problem.
That was one thing that was going
to lead up to ultimately a problem.
Second, investment banks in the United
States were leveraging their capital 30
and 40 times the capital. It was
outrageous. Going from say five and six times,
seven times your capital, to 40 and
50 and 30 times your capital was obviously
a risk that shouldn't have been taken. The SEC
just ignored that fact. Why? It's hard to understand.
But it was clear that we were setting in motion some conditions
that would be very difficult to live with on a real time basis.
And of course, it's going to cause problems. Then some of these
investment banks said, look, our job is to be creative and create products.
Then some of these investment banks said, look,
our job is to be creative and create products.
So they took some of these mortgages that were being now written
for people who didn't have really the right to own a home.
They just didn't have the financial needs.
They didn't have the financial background for it.
They packaged these mortgages into a product.
They took mortgages, they said, from the east, the west, the south, and
the northeast, put them all together and said, the diversification of the market,
because the diversification is terrific, and that means
you can have, it will be marked AAA.
They went to the rating agencies and sold the rating agencies, Moody's
and the rest, that these, this diversification, they deserve a AAA rating.
And the rating agencies accommodated them. Didn't do very
much analysis of their own and they were marked AAA.
They sold these mortgages, these products, these
CDOs, to every client and customer they
could find all around the world.
And of course, they weren't AAA.
And then, as I said earlier, these credit
default swaps that would respond to a, normally
a default had been changed so that
you responded to just a reduction in value.
It just blew up in everybody's face.
The same time they were doing all
of this, the accounting principles board, located here
in Connecticut, came out with mark-to-market accounting.
They couldn't have picked a worse time to do that.
And that marked balance sheets that you normally
would carry, say, at cost or held to maturity
where you keep the value.
You had to mark it down to a market value.
And that destroyed capital artificially in many instances.
That never should have happened.
SCC who oversees that kept silent.
So you had all of these things come together.
Yeah.
at the same time that led
to the destruction that took place.
There are other things that happened.
I can go through a list of them,
but I don't think the real story
of what truly occurred in our country
has been fully recognized yet.
Generally, it'll take a while.
There have been a lot of books written,
but generally on parts of it, not the entire issue.
I testified before a couple
of congressional committees on this,
particularly on the AIG issue.
For example, by what right did the government have
to take essentially 92% of AIG?
To me, it was an unlawful taking.
What should have been done,
and if you look at the other companies
that they...
that they aided,
they aided Citigroup,
and they got about 30% of the equity.
That's different than 92%.
They aided several other companies the same way.
So why was AIG
really set aside
and used the way it was?
AIG was a national asset.
We have no insurance company.
It operates globally.
It's a national asset.
It's a national asset globally in 130 countries.
When I tell you it's a national asset,
I know what I'm talking about.
Because we did many things that were beneficial
to our country and our government.
And it was totally destroyed.
They saved Goldman's...
AIG was used to save many, including Goldman Sachs.
But that story will come out.
I'm not sure.
It's been alleged already in the newspapers
and in articles and magazines.
And you have it.
But anyway, I think I'll stop right here
and take questions.
So we have microphones here.
So if you have any questions,
we'll get to them.
No?
Yeah, cool.
So when you were talking
about the culture of your organization,
you mentioned that you do not prefer having contracts
with your employees.
And I'm wondering what that means not to have contracts.
And why do you do it?
I didn't quite understand.
Contracts.
I think that you ought to
hold and should have a contract
that you stay if you weren't doing the job.
But you have to start someplace.
And it started with me.
I refused a contract.
I thought that if I wasn't doing the job,
I shouldn't be forced to stay in the company.
They should have a right to have a new CEO.
So I turned it down.
Is that because the contract couldn't be explicit?
Well, no.
The contract say that if you have a five-year contract,
at the end of three years,
if the company's not doing well,
why should the company be forced
to keep you for two more years?
If you don't ask me a question,
I'll ask you some questions.
I have a question.
I'm not talking to anybody.
So I guess this is more of a personal question.
I was wondering what, so we're all in school,
and we don't have jobs yet.
And so in thinking about careers,
it's an important decision.
So I was wondering what
made you really enjoy your job.
Was it the success you had?
Was it the day-to-day activities?
Was it the impact you made?
I don't know.
I think it's the impact you
made on being a part of AIG.
Well, I think there's many things.
You have to love what you do to begin with.
And I love building.
And I love working with a
group of people that we had.
It was a very close group.
And it was a lot of fun opening new markets
and beating our competitors.
It was a very satisfying experience.
And you have to love it.
You have to have,
the other thing I would say,
you need a lot of energy.
You got to want,
you know, work is,
you know, work should not be viewed as a,
you know, from nine to five.
You work as long as you have to
because you love doing it.
This also kind of reminds me of Bear Stearns
and another very,
very experienced chairman,
Ace Greenberg,
kind of warning his board.
I'm not hearing you.
This is on.
This, like AIG,
the story of AIG really
reminds me of Bear Stearns' fall
and of a really experienced,
you know, board member pointing out
that what the company was doing wasn't great.
So can you talk to,
I guess,
the idea of having experience in this field
and the fact that,
you know, companies were kind of,
boards weren't working was also like a core problem.
And the financial crisis.
So can you tell me
a little bit more about that
and how you felt afterwards?
I didn't quite hear that.
Would you,
did you hear?
Boards were not working properly.
Boards were not working properly is absolutely right.
The,
there was a lead director in the company.
Look, we had a,
if you go back through the history of AIG,
we had some outstanding people on the board.
Over a period of time,
some retire, some die.
But we had,
we had a pretty good board.
Carla Hills, for example,
was on the board.
She was an outstanding director.
She had been in the cabinet of
George Bush I.
She was,
she was a terrific director.
Bill Cohen, who had been Secretary of Defense,
was a director.
And,
Dick Holbrook recently died as a director.
So we had some good directors.
On the other hand,
when,
when Spitzer threatened the company,
many of them
just folded.
Not Carla Hills and not Bill Cohen,
but many others.
And,
you don't know how people
are going to respond until they're
confronted with a,
with an issue.
But,
there's no question that the board failed,
in my judgment,
to recognize what was happening after I left.
So China has recently been experiencing rapid growth.
How do you think their growth,
the change toward a consumption model,
will change the insurance industry in China?
The China you're saying has been growing rapidly?
How will that change the insurance industry in China?
The insurance industry in China,
how is it changing in their,
in their rapid growth?
It's changed dramatically.
The largest insurance company in the world today,
by market value,
is China Life.
Amazing growth in China.
And you'd expect it,
China has passed the United States,
in the number of automobiles
being built in the United States,
in the number of automobiles being sold a year.
They won't have to be insured.
So the growth in the insurance industry in China,
is very rapid.
Very,
in a way yet,
very immature in many ways,
in understanding risk.
But that'll,
that'll change.
But they've,
they've come a long ways.
When I first went to China,
and we entered our life company,
the life insurance industry in China was very small.
And they didn't have agents,
selling life insurance.
They had their employees,
So if an employee,
sold something,
he would get paid.
And he'd,
he'd get paid whether he sold or not.
So they had a fixed expense.
We introduced,
an agency system in China,
and recruited thousands of people,
thousands of agents.
And they got commissions,
if they sold something.
If they didn't sell,
they didn't get a commission.
They,
the Chinese companies quickly adapted to our system.
So you could say that we
created millions and millions of jobs,
in China.
All right.
So,
thank you.
I'm just wondering what do you think,
a chartist in Sun America,
currently,
saw businesses and how you would evaluate,
Robert Bennett,
his job as the current CEO?
Look, I've known Bob Ben-Moshe for,
15, 20 years.
And he's a decent man.
He's a good man.
And he's, I think, a pretty good,
good leader.
He has very little experience internationally.
And his experience has been in the life insurance sector,
not in the non-life sector.
And the,
one of the largest components of AIG,
is the non-life,
sector.
So he's,
he's got a hard job,
in front of him.
Also,
the most valuable assets have been sold.
The AIA,
which is,
the company that's entered in China,
that AIG owns 100% of.
They sold that.
Which I wouldn't have done.
And they sold,
American life to,
to metropolitan life.
That company does business in 55 countries,
around the world.
You can't replicate that.
I wouldn't have sold that.
So,
AIG is a shadow of what it was before.
Ben-Moshe's got a tough job.
He's a,
he doesn't know the non-life business very well.
And the culture of the company has been,
is gone.
Most of the people who work there,
who were some of the better people,
have left.
Uh,
many have come to me.
Working in,
in CV Star Company,
and in our agencies,
and our insurance companies.
Um,
it's gonna be a tough job.
But he's a good man,
I like him.
Hi,
good morning.
Uh,
during your speech,
you alluded to the destructive power of,
credit default swaps.
And,
uh,
what I find interesting is,
different countries have taken a very different approach.
Some European countries have absolutely banned,
credit default swaps.
China most notably introduced them in the market recently,
but,
put a cap on the value with the underlying amount.
Uh,
so my question really is,
what sort of regulation do you think would work well,
both at the national level,
and possibly the international level?
Uh,
that's a good question.
I would do,
at least two things.
First,
I would go back to a,
where credit default swap,
would only respond if the underlying instrument,
that it is,
supposedly insuring,
uh,
defaults.
In other words,
I would not respond,
to just a reduction in value.
Um,
because,
if you look at all those CDOs that were,
that were,
that the,
that the credit default swaps,
were covering,
most of those have recovered in value.
Okay?
So that,
there was a temporary,
reduction in value,
but they didn't default.
And so,
what it does is,
it's a,
and so what it led to,
was unnecessary chaos in the market.
The second thing I would have,
is an exchange,
um,
where,
you could,
where you get price discovery,
um,
without price discovery,
you're back where you were.
And so you have to have that.
And you'd have to put up reserves.
If I was gonna issue credit default swaps,
you ought to reserve it like a...
if it's gonna be an insurance instrument,
treat it like an insurance instrument.
And,
and make you,
underlying company who's issuing them put up reserves.
It can be a bit
intimidating sometimes to hear or learn
or read about the insurance industry because
of the regulation and the billions and billions of dollars
that are always involved, et cetera, as a student.
But I'm wondering, in addition to what you're doing yourself
now with CVStar, what opportunities
do you see for entrepreneurship in the insurance industry
today, if any?
I think there's tremendous opportunity
for being an entrepreneur.
You know, you're living in a changing world,
changing economies.
New products are being invented and developed every day.
And investments are going on
in different parts of the world.
All of that needs insurance.
And so there's great opportunity
to be creative in the insurance
industry and differentiate yourself from everybody else.
I'm about to do a
joint venture insurance company in China.
The one we're doing a joint venture with
is a very traditional company.
We will change that in less
than a year into something different.
And it's exciting to do that.
So I'm looking forward to it.
Thank you.
嗨
Do you think that, I
mean, with the recent financial crisis,
we've seen a lot of government intervention and interaction
in the private world.
And I was wondering, do you think that the government
should have any role other than just keeping things fair?
Do you think they should intervene
when these companies are having big issues, having to AIG?
Do I think government should intervene?
I think that the least amount that's necessary.
I don't think that, I think that if you're
asking the question, too big to fail,
I think there are some institutions that probably
would cause chaos if they failed.
But I would make that
very, very few and far between.
But what troubles me is what happened in this recession
and government intervention.
They picked and chose who they wanted to save
and who they didn't.
It wasn't even-handed.
It was done with the intent
to save some and not others.
The real story of what
happened has not been printed yet.
After all, it's very common knowledge
that Paulson, who was then Treasury Secretary,
was surrounded by Goldman Sachs people.
I'm not making that up.
That happens to be a fact.
And I'm not making that up.
I'm not making that up.
And so how objective were
they in what they were deciding
to do and not do?
I think that there are times government has to intervene.
But I happen to believe in the private sector,
the ability of Americans to create jobs and businesses.
And government should be small.
Government created jobs are not the best jobs.
Private sector jobs are the best jobs, in my judgment.
Water 그걸?
Thank you.
Okay, next question?
What role do you think that banks should play
in the future to avoid a similar crisis?
And do you think that there
needs to be a different sense
of what risk has priority and direction,
iges to be muscles and seize on viable viability,
What's the last part?
What kind of role should banks play in the future?
And do you think that there needs to
be a different definition of what risk is?
What risk is?
Risk.
Yeah, okay.
When you say banks, you have to
differentiate between commercial banks and investment banks.
Look, I think that the Dodd-Frank bill that
has been passed comes up with a whole new
set of regulations.
Let me touch on that in a minute.
And will banks use their own capital
to do transactions that puts the whole institution
at risk?
Probably will not be the way it was.
I think the Volcker Rule, which would
limit the amount of individual transactions that
might be in the bank.
That might endanger the bank, going to be
limited and have to use an off-balance sheet
approach so that that doesn't
pollute the rest of the bank.
Investment banks, for example, that may have
done transactions that bet against their own
clients I think should be outlawed.
If an investment bank is selling me, say,
investing in the XYZ CDOs, and then they take
a position against that.
It seems to me that that's
immoral and should not be permitted.
Now, the Dodd-Frank bill was enacted before they
even had any of the response of all the
investigations that were going on.
It seems to me they should have waited
and hear what the investigators had come up with
before they passed a new law.
Now the Congress has to provide for the fund.
I think that's a good thing.
And I think that's a good thing for the
financing of all these new regulators that are going
to be created under the Dodd-Frank bill.
And I'm not sure that's going to happen.
I'm not so sure that all of them are necessary.
Well, we need better regulators, not more regulation.
We had plenty of regulations.
If they had enforced the regulations that
were in existence, we would have avoided a
great deal, if not all, of what took place.
One more question?
All right.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
哎
You mentioned earlier about how AIG attracted
and retained the best people in the business,
and that's how they grew,
because of the strong culture there.
But if you're starting a new company, or even
entering in a management position at a current company,
how do you go about building that
type of culture that just fosters growth?
How do you build the culture that you're talking about?
The culture starts at the top.
It's got to start with the individual running the company.
And the same thing as I say in risk management.
The CEO is the top risk manager in the company.
You have other people involved, but you're the risk manager.
You decide how much risk you really want to take.
The same thing is true in culture.
You build a culture based upon your performance,
what you stand for, what you believe in,
and you surround yourself with people
who are going to help you.
People who share those beliefs.
If they don't, they'll feel out of step.